Register to The Henry Gilbert Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, 1891-1927; Series I; 11.9' (20 boxes)
  - Songs, I.E
    - [I doan want you hangin' round] (Box 12, Folder 183)
      See also: Oh! What I know about you.
      - I don't want you hangin' round / music by Frank Belknap [pseudonym]., 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
      - Coon song: I doan want you hangin' round / words by Karl Tausig; music by Frank Belknap., 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
      - [I doan want you hangin' round], 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm.
    - [I want to marry my merry Marie...], 1 score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 184)
      Words by Louisa S. Tausig.
    - Ill wind that blew somebody good
    - [In her hand..], 1 score ([3] p.); 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 185)
    - [In May], 1 score ([1] p.); 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 186)
      Words by Heine.
      Dated: 1891 Aug 30.
      "In May - song. Earhert (?) dated HG work" - folder.
    - [Inconvenient], 1 score ([1] sheet); 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 187)
      Words and music by Henry F. Gilbert."
      "No. 4" - p. [1].
    - [Island of Tortuga... (Sketches)] (Box 12, Folder 188)
      - [Island of Tortuga... (Sketches)], 1 score (6 p.); 34 cm.
      - [Island of Tortuga... (Sketches)], 1 score ([2] p.); 35 cm.
    - [It must have been the milkman] (Box 12, Folder 189)
      - It must have been the milkman / Lyric by Karl Tausig; music by Frank Belknap [pseudonym]., 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
        "Copyright, 1908 by Karl Tausig" - p. [1].
      - [It must have been the milkman], 1 score (5 p.); 36 cm.
    - [It must have been the milkman (Sketch)], [1] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 189)
      With: Let's go to the movie picture show.
    - [It seems to me where e'er I go... (Sketch)], [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 190)
    - [Lament], [1] sheet of music; 27 cm. (Box 12, Folder 191)
      Holograph signed, in ink with pencil "R" written over the music.
      For unacc. voice?
      See also: Mournful linnets.
    - [Lament of Deirdré] (Box 12, Folder 192)
      - [Lament of Deirdré], 1 score ([4] p.); 34 cm.
        Words translated from the Gaelic by Sir Samuel Ferguson.
        "Copyright, 1903, by the Wa-Wan Press" - p. 1.
        [Op.3, no. 3].
      - [Lament of Deirdré], 1 score ([4] p.); 34 cm.
        "Irish lament" - crossed out title.
    - [Lament of Deirdré; arr.] (Box 12, Folder 192)
      - [Lament of Deirdré; arr.], 1 score (4 p.); 31 cm.
      - [Lament of Deirdré; arr.], 1 score (4 p.); 31 cm.
      - [Lament of Deirdré; arr.], 1 score (pp. 4-7); 35 cm.
        Contains pencil markings by Henry Gilbert.
        With: "I look into my glass" by Alfred E. Little; and "Love's secret" by Arthur Farwell.
      - Irish lament, 1 score (6, [1] p.); 35 cm.
        Arr. for voice and orchestra.
        Lacking words.
    - [Lament of Deirdré (Sketch)], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 192)
      Sheet labeled 'Projected and incomplete devts. of "Lament of Deirdre"' laid in.
      See also: F. Voice and Instrumental Ensemble. Lament of Deirdré.
    - [Let's go to a moving picture show], 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 193)
      [Words by Karl Tausig].
      Ca. 1909.
      "It must have been the milkman (Sketch)" - on back.
    - [Little sailor], 1 score ([1] p.); 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 194)
    - [Loafing souvenir] (Box 12, Folder 195)
      - [Loafing souvenir], 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm.
        Music by "Hank" [pseudonym].
        Words by "Fritz" [pseudonym for Frederick Manley].
      - [unittitle added: see error report]
        1 photocopy of the above score.
    - [Love-lit sapphires of your eyes], 1 score ([5] p.); 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 195)
      Words by Frederick Manley.
    - [Love song] (Box 12, Folder 196)
      - [Love song], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
      - [Love song], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
    - [Lullaby] (Box 12, Folder 196)
      - [Lullaby], 1 score ([1] sheet); 36 cm.
        Words from "The nursery."
        "Copyright, 1922, by Henry F. Gilbert."
        No. 12.
      - [Lullaby], [1] sheet of music; 14 x 21 cm.
    - [Mayor of Scuttleton (Sketch)], [9] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 197)
    - [Mayor of Scuttleton. Text], [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 13, Folder 197)
      From "Rhymes and Jingles" by Mary Mapes Dodge. Charles Scribner's Sons."
      "Song del'd Feb. 16."
      See also: G. Choral. Mayor of Scuttleton.
    - Merry-go-round
    - [Midnight] (Box 13, Folder 198)
      - [Midnight], 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm.
        Words by Heinrich Heine.
        Dated: 1893 Jul 31.
      - [Midnight], 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm.
    - [Mittenacht (Sketch)], [1] sheet of music; 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 198)
      Not the same setting as "Midnight."
    - Montonéra
      See: South American gypsy songs.
    - [Moon voyage] (Box 13, Folder 199)
      - [Moon voyage], 1 score ([1] sheet); 36 cm.
      - [Moon voyage], 1 score ([1] sheet); 31 cm.
        Three copies, 1 with note by Henry Gilbert, another cut and pasted to be used as proof sheets.
    - [Mother's become a suffragette] (Box 13, Folder 200)
      - [Mother's become a suffragette], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
        "Copyright 1908 by Karl Tausig, Lyrics."
      - [Mother's become a suffragette], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
    - [Mournful linnets (Sketch)], [1] sheet of music; 16 x 27 cm. (Box 13, Folder 201)
      See also: Lament.
    - [Music everywhere (first version)], [1] sheet of music; 15 x 27 cm. (Box 13, Folder 202)
      For unacc. voice.
      In 4/4 time.
    - [Music everywhere (second version)], [1] sheet of music; 15 x 27 cm. (Box 13, Folder 202)
      In 3/4 time.
    - [My gal's a heavy swell (Sketch)], [1] sheet of music; 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 203)
    - [Necken's polka (Sketch)], 1 score ([1] sheet); 27 x 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 204)
      Sketch for Song of Wermeland on back.
      See also: I. Miscellaneous Works. Sketchbooks.
    - [O were my love yon lilac fair] (Box 13, Folder 205)
      - [O were my love yon lilac fair], 1 score ([2] p.); 35 cm.
        Dated: 1894 Nov 11.
      - [O were my love yon lilac fair], 1 score ([2] p.); 35 cm.
      - [O were my love yon lilac fair], 1 score ([2] p.); 31 cm.
        Professional copy.
      - [O were my love yon lilac fair], 1 score ([2] p.); 31 cm.
    - [O when I hear at sea... (Sketch)], 1 score ([4] p.); 33 cm. (Box 13, Folder 206)
    - [O would I were the cool wind... (Sketch)], [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 207)
    - [Oh look upon the bright side...], 1 score (5 p.) 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 208)
    - [Oh look upon the bright side... (Sketch)], [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 208)
    - [Oh! What I know about you] (Box 13, Folder 209)
      - [Oh! What I know about you], 1 score (pp. 1-3); 32 cm.
        With: Henry Gilbert's "I doan want you hangin' round" as well as songs by several others.
        Two copies headed "Professional copy."
        "All ready to orchestrate now" - p. 1.
      - Oh! What I know about you / Lyric by Karl Tausig; music by Frank Belknap [pseudonym]. - Boston: C.W. Thompson & Co., c1909., 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm.
    - [One night as I did wander], 1 score ([1] sheet); 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 210)
    - [Orlamonde] Orlamonde / [words by] Maurice Maeterlinck; translated by Mary J. Serrano. - Newton Center, Mass.: Wa-Wan Press, c1907., 1 score (7 p.); 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 211)
    - [Owl] (Box 13, Folder 212)
      - [Owl], 1 score ([41 p.); 34 cm.
        Poem by Tennyson.
        "Copyright 1910 by H.F. Gilbert" - p. [1].
      - [Owl], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
        Pencil sketch on back.
      - [Owl], 1 score ([3] p.); 35 cm.
        "Incorrect copy" - in pencil on p. [1].
      - [Owl], 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm.
    - [Perdita] (Box 13, Folder 213)
      - Perdita / [music by] Frank Belknap [pseudonym]; [words by] James T. Fields., 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
      - [Perdita], 1 score (3 p.); 31 cm.
      - [Perdita], 1 score (pp. 2-3); 32 cm.
      - [Perdita], Proof sheets for cover of copy published by Gilbert; 36 cm.
        Positive and negative with insert attached to the negative.
    - Pigtail
    - [Pirate song] (Box 13, Folder 214)
      - [Pirate song], 1 scare (4 p.); 35 cm.
        Words adapted from Stevenson's "Treasure Island," additional stanzas by Alice C. Hyde.
        Volume IV: Autumn quarter.
      - [Pirate song], 1 score (4 p.); 31 cm.
        See also: F. Voice and Instrumental Ensemble. Pirate song; arr.
    - [Poor young shepherd], 1 score ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 215)
      Words by Paul Verlaine.
    - [Pop corn], 1 score ([1] p.); 33 cm. (Box 13, Folder 216)
      "Copyright 1922 by Henry F. Gilbert - p. [1].
      "No. 11" - p. [1].
    - [Pop in and see your Poppy...], 1 score ([1] p.); 33 cm. (Box 13, Folder 217)
      Chorus only.
    - [Princess Ilse], 1 score ([1] sheet); 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 218)
    - [Proud Maisie] (Box 13, Folder 219)
      - [Proud Maisie], 1 score ([4] p.); 34 cm.
        Music by "Old mortality" [pseudonym?].
        Words by Walter Scott.
      - [Proud Maisie], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
    - [Proud Maisie (Sketch)], 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 219)
    - [Puzzled] (Box 13, Folder 220)
      - [Puzzled], 1 score ([1] sheet); 36 cm.
      - [Puzzled], 1 score (113 sheet); 31 cm.
      - [Puzzled], Proof sheet for the above printed score; 22 x 28 cm.
        "No. 8."
    - [Puzzled. Text], [1] sheet; 23 cm. (Box 13, Folder 220)
      "Copyright, 1915 by the Rocking Chair Syndicate."
    - [Requiem] (Box 13, Folder 221)
      - [Requiem], 1 score ([4] p.); 33 cm.
        Words by Robert Louis Stevenson.
        Dated: 1918 Sep 10.
      - [Requiem], 1 score (5 p.); 33 cm.
      - [Requiem], 1 score ([3] p.); 35 cm.
      - [Requiem], 1 score (5 p.); 34 cm.
        "N.G. see later copy" - in pencil on cover.
      - [Requiem], 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm.
    - [Requiem (Sketches)], Loose sheets ([14] p.); 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 221)
    - [Ring out, wild bells... (Sketch)], [2] p.; 27 x 36 cm. (Box 13, Folder 222)
    - [Robin redbreast], 1 score ([1] p.); 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 223)
      Words by Frank Sweet.
    - [Rocking chair], 1 score ([2] p.); 36 cm. (Box 13, Folder 224)
      "Copyright, 1922 by Henry F. Gilbert" p. [1].
      "No. 1."
      "Only 5 Rocking chair songs - published, printed" - folder.
      See: Clinkum Clankum; Cold lunch; Dollykins; Down the ladder; A funny fact; Inconvenient; Lullaby; Moon voyage; Puzzled; Rocking chair; Snow-man; and A tragic mistake.
    - [Roses are a regal troop...], 1 score ([1] p.); 24 cm. (Box 13, Folder 225)
      Words by T.B. Aldrich.
      Dated: 1893 Jul 28.
    - [Rouse for Roosevelt] (Box 13, Folder 226)
      - [Rouse for Roosevelt], 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm.
        Words by George L. Farwell.
        [1912].
      - Rouse for Roosevelt: campaign song. - Newton Center, Mass. George L. Farwell, c1912., 1 score (3 p.); 28 cm.
    - [Rouse for Roosevelt (Sketches)], Loose sheets ([32] p. of music); 36 cm. (Box 13, Folder 226)
      Contains cornet, trumpet, tuba, and drum parts for an arr.
    - [Rouse for Roosevelt. Text], [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 13, Folder 226)
      Note on bottom of the page from George L. Farwell, 1921 Apr 22.
      See also: F. Voice and Instrumental Ensemble. Rouse for Roosevelt; arr.
    - [Salammbô's invocation to Tänith] Salammbô - Chapter III Invocation to the moon-goddess / [words by] Flaubert. (Box 13, Folder 227)
      See also: B. Orchestra- Salammbô's Invocation; and F. Voice and Instrumental Ensemble. Salammbô's ...; arr.
      - [Salammbô's invocation to Tänith] Salammbô - Chapter III Invocation to the moon-goddess / [words by] Flaubert., 1 score (7 p.); 35 cm.
      - [Salammbô's invocation to Tänith] Salammbô - Chapter III Invocation to the moon-goddess / [words by] Flaubert., 1 score (6 p.); 31 cm.
      - [Salammbô's invocation to Tänith] Salammbô - Chapter III Invocation to the moon-goddess / [words by] Flaubert., 1 score (pp. 10-15); 35 cm.
        Contains pencil markings by Henry Gilbert?
        With: Arthur Reginald Little's "Helen" and "Drink to me only with thine eyes."
    - Scotch song
      See: Curl.
    - Signs of spring
    - [Sleep and poetry], [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 228)
      Words by Keats.
    - [Sleighing song], [1] sheet of music; 20 x 27 cm. (Box 13, Folder 229)
      Sketch on back entitled "La Za-?"
      "School songs" - folder.
      See also: Wind.
    - [Slumber song], 1 score ([1] p.); 27 cm. (Box 12, Folder 149)
      With: Scherzo.
      See: Chamber and Instrumental. Scherzo.
    - [Snow-man] (Box 13, Folder 230)
      - [Snow-man], 1 score ([1] p.); 36 cm.
      - [Snow-man], 1 score ([1] sheet); 32 cm.
        "No. 10" - in pencil on 1 copy.
    - [Snow-man. Text], [1] sheet; 17 x 23 cm. (Box 13, Folder 230)
    - [Song of Wermeland (Sketch)], 1 score ([1] sheet); 27 x 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 204)
      On back of Necken's polka (Sketch).
    - Songs, op. 1
      See: Fair Helen; and Group of songs.
    - [Sound as of marching myriad feet...], [1] sheet of music; 20 x 27 cm. (Box 13, Folder 231)
      Holograph signed, in ink with pencil signature.
      Includes 2 versions.
    - [South American gypsy songs] Published separately: New York H.W. Gray, c1906., 4 scores; 31-35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 232)
      For violin (ad. lib.), voice, and piano.
      Words from "Through Romany songland" by Laura A. Smith.
      Contents: No. I. La Montonéra - No. II. La Zambulidora.
      Two copies of each song as well as 4 proof sheets, one of which contains pencil markings for No. 1.
    - [Stirrup cup], 1 score (5 p.); 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 233)
      Words by Sydney Lanier.
      "Study" noted above title.
    - [Sweetheart when you kiss me please don't leave a mark] (Box 13, Folder 234)
      - [Sweetheart when you kiss me please don't leave a mark], 1 score (5 p.); 34 cm.
      - [Sweetheart when you kiss me please don't leave a mark], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
      - [Sweetheart when you kiss me please don't leave a mark], 1 score ([4] p.); 34 cm.
    - [Tell me where is fancy bred], 1 score (141 p.); 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 235)
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections pasted on, and pencil markings.
      Words by Shakespeare.
      "2nd proof - Feb - 21 - '05" - in blue pencil on first page.
      "Copyright 1905 by H.F. Gilbert" - first page.
    - [Thanksgiving day in Boston Harbor (Sketch)?], [3] p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 13, Folder 236)
      Typescript of text laid in.
    - [Thanksgiving day in Boston Harbor. Text], [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 13, Folder 236)
      Words by Hezekiah Butterworth (From "American Anthology").
    - [That dream-girl of mine] That dream-girl of mine / lyric by George A. Harris; music by Frank Belknap [pseudonym]., 1 score ([3] sheets); 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 237)
      Holograph signed (photostat-negative).
      "Copyright, 1926, by Harris and Belknap" p. 1.
    - [That dream-girl of mine (Sketch)] (Box 13, Folder 237)
      - [That dream-girl of mine (Sketch)], 1 score (4 p.); 35 cm.
        Holograph signed, in ink with pencil markings; words in part typescript, pasted on.
      - [That dream-girl of mine (Sketch)], Photograph (negative) of the above score; 22 cm.
    - [That dream-girl of mine. Text], [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 13, Folder 237)
      Typescript with pencil sketch.
      With: Here's hoping. Text.
    - [There once was a frog... (Sketch)], [1] sheet of music; 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 238)
      With sketches labeled "1924" by Henry Gilbert.
    - [Torrent] (Box 13, Folder 239)
      - [Torrent], [1] sheet of music; 17 x 25 cm.
      - [Torrent], [1] sheet of music; 13 x 25 cm.
    - [Tragic mistake], 1 score ([1] p.); 36 cm. (Box 13, Folder 240)
      "Copyright, 1922 by Henry F. Gilbert" - p. 1.
      "No - 7" - p. 1.
    - [Treasure of the wise man] (Box 13, Folder 241)
      - [Treasure of the wise man], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
        Holograph signed, in ink with correction pasted on and pencil markings.
        Words by James Whitcomb Riley.
      - [Treasure of the wise man], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
        Holograph signed, in ink with corrections pasted on and pencil markings.
      - [Treasure of the wise man], 1 score ([3] sheets); 31 cm.
    - [Treasure of the wise man (Sketch)], [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 241)
    - [Tubal Cain], [1] sheet of music; 22 x 27 cm. (Box 13, Folder 242)
      Holograph signed, in ink with title and signature in pencil.
    - [Twilight at sea], 1 score ([2] p.); 32 cm. (Box 13, Folder 243)
      For voice, piano, and 2 unidentified voices or instruments.
    - [Vspo mni vspo mni moi liubez...(Sketch)], 1 score ([1] sheet); 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 244)
      Text in Old Russian?
    - [Waltz song], 1 score ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 245)
      Words by Bertram Shapleigh.
    - [When you kiss your last good night], 1 score (3 p.); 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 246)
    - [Wind], [1] sheet of music; 14 x 27 cm. (Box 13, Folder 247)
      Words by R.L. Stevenson.
      Sketch entitled "La Za[mbulidora?]" on back.
      See also: Sleighing song; and South American gypsy songs.
    - [Windward] (Box 13, Folder 248)
      - [Windward], 1 score (5 p.); 34 cm.
      - [Windward], 1 score (5 p.); 34 cm.
        Holograph signed, in ink with corrections pasted on.
    - [Winter], 1 score ([1] p.); 35 cm. (Box 13, Folder 249)
      Words by Shelley.
    - [Won't you please play house with me] (Box 13, Folder 250)
      - [Won't you please play house with me], 1 score ([3] p.); 35 cm.
      - [Won't you please play house with me], 1 score ([1] sheet); 34 cm.
        Lacking chorus.
    - [Won't you please play house with me. Chorus#1], 1 score ([1] sheet) 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 250)
    - [Won't you please play house with me. Chorus#3], 1 score ([1] sheet) 34 cm. (Box 13, Folder 250)
      Sketch on back.
    - Zambulidora
    - [Zephyrus] (Box 13, Folder 251)
      - [Zephyrus], 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm.
        Manuscript in ink with pencil note.
      - [Zephyrus], 1 score (5 p.); 36 cm.
    - Miscellaneous unidentified sketches for songs and song texts, Loose sheets ([39] p.); 16 x 36 cm. (Box 13, Folder 252)
      Includes sketches labeled "School songs for Ginn and Co."
      See also: IX.A. WRITINGS. By Gilbert. Texts, synopsises, and notes for Henry Gilbert's musical works.
  - Voice and Instrumental Ensemble, I.F
    - [Autumn], 1 score ([3] p.); 27 x 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 253)
      Words by Percy Bysshe Shelley.
      "No. 1" - p. 1.
    - [Curl; arr.] Scotch song, 1 score (5 p.); 27 x 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 254)
      Words by Amelie Rives.
      "No. 2. The Curl" - cover.
      Op. 3/2.
      See also: E. Songs. Curl.
    - [Fair Helen; arr.?], 1 score ([4] p.); 27 x 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 255)
      See also: E. Songs. Fair Helen, and Group of songs.
    - Irish lament
      See: Lament of Deirdré; arr.?
    - [Lament of Deirdré; arr.?] Irish lament: no. 3, 1 score ([8] p.); 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 256)
      Words by S. Ferguson.
      Op. 3/3.
    - [Mittenacht war kalt...], 1 score (7 p.); 27 x 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 257)
      For voice and orchestra.
      Words by Heine written before but not in score.
    - [Pirate song; arr. (Sketch)], 1 score (14 p.); 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 258)
      See also: G. Choral. Pirate song; arr.
    - [Rouse for Roosevelt; arr.], 4 parts ([1] p.); 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 259)
      Includes cornet II, trumpet I, and tuba I-II parts.
      Pencil sketches on back of parts.
      See also: E. Songs. Rouse for Roosevelt.
    - [Salammbô's invocation to Tänith; arr.]
      - [Salammbô's invocation to Tänith; arr.], 1 score (19 p.), bound; 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 260)
        For soprano and orchestra.
        [1902].
        [Op. 6].
      - [Salammbô's invocation to Tänith; arr.], Photostat (negative) of the above holograph score; 25, 24 x 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 261)
      - [Salammbô's invocation to Tänith; arr.], 1 score (19 p.); 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 262)
        Holograph signed, in pencil and ink with orange pencil markings.
      - [Salammbô's invocation to Tänith; arr.], 34 parts; 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 263)
      - [Salammbô's invocation to Tänith; arr.], 21 parts; 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 264)
        Holographs signed, in ink; harp in unidentified hand.
      - [Salammbô's invocation to Tänith; arr.], 30 parts; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 265)
        Holographs signed, in ink and manuscript in ink.
    - Scotch song
      See: Curl; arr.
  - Choral, I.G
    - [All hail, America] S.l.: s.n., no date, 1 close score ([2] p.); 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 266)
      Two copies, clipped from an unidentified journal.
      Typescript copy of the words ([1] sheet) laid in.
    - [Anthems], 1 sketchbook ([22] p. of music); 19 x 26 cm. (Box 14, Folder 267)
      Loose pencil sketches ([6] p.), one signed by Elizabeth Gilbert, laid in.
      "Solo. Soprano 1" - cover.
      Contents: I will arise - Abide with me - The Lord is my shepherd.
    - [Chorale (Sketch)], [6] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 268)
    - [Columbus] Columbus / [words by] Joaquin Miller. - Boston: C.C. Birchard, c1916., 1 score (4 p.); 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 268)
      For unison chorus.
    - [How pleasant how divinely fair... (Sketch)], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 269)
    - [Hymn of prayer] (Box 14, Folder 270)
      - [Hymn of prayer], 1 close score ([1] sheet); 34 cm.
        Words by Prof. Henry Hallam Tweedy.
        Enclosed in typed letter from the Homiletic Review to Mrs. Henry Gilbert postmarked 1926 Dec 2-? along with "Strength for the day."
      - [Hymn of prayer], 1 close score ([1] sheet); 34 cm.
        Enclosed in typed letter from the Homiletic Review to Henry Gilbert postmarked 1926 Dec 15, along with "Longing."
    - [Jabberwock (Sketch)], [5] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 271)
      For chorus of men and women and orchestra (arr. for piano?).
    - [Longing (first setting)], 1 close score ([1] sheet); 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 272)
      Words by H.R. MacFayden.
      Second setting on same sheet.
      Enclosed in typed letter from the Homiletic Review to Henry Gilbert postmarked 1926 Dec 15.
    - [Longing (second setting)], 1 close score ([1] sheet); 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 272)
    - [Mayor of Scuttleton. Text], [1] p. (p.297) of music; 25 cm. (Box 14, Folder 276)
      In: Damrosch's Universal school music series along with Henry Gilbert's "Thanksgiving in Boston Harbor."
      See: "Thanksgiving in Boston Harbor."
      See also: E. Songs. Mayor of Scuttleton (Sketch).
    - [My neighbor's dog] My neighbor's dog / [music by] Frank Belknap [pseudonym] [words by] Nixon Waterman. - Boston: C.C. Birchard, c1904., 1 score (4 p.); 27 cm. (Box 14, Folder 273)
      For chorus (SATB).
    - [Pirate song; arr.], 1 score (14 sheets); 22 cm. (Box 14, Folder 274)
      Arr. for baritone, male voices, and orchestra.
      [1921].
      See also: F. Voice and Instrumental Ensemble. Pirate song; arr. (Sketch).
    - [Rain song] Rain song / [words by] Nixon Waterman. - S.l.: C.C. Birchard, c1904., 1 score ([4] p.); 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 275)
      For chorus (SAB) and piano.
    - [Strength for the day], 1 close score ([1] sheet); 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 275)
      Words by Henry Webb Farrington.
      Enclosed in typed letter from the Homiletic Review to Henry Gilbert postmarked 1926-? along with "Hymn of prayer."
    - [Thanksgiving in Boston Harbor] [In: Damrosch's Universal School Music Reader]: New York, etc.: Hinds, Hayden & Eldridge, c1924., 1 score (pp. 198-201), bound; 25 cm. (Box 14, Folder 276)
      For chorus (SSAB), acc.
    - [Thunder maker] Boston: C.C. Birchard, c1913., 1 score (4 p.); 28 cm. (Box 14, Folder 277)
      For mixed chorus.
    - [To Thee! America] To Thee! America: Hymn; for mixed chorus and orchestra (Box 14, Folder 278)